Is this the Idanokan Palace?
這裡是伊達諾坎的王宮嗎
We actually made it back?
我們成功回來了嗎
It's too dark to see anything in here.
太暗了 看不太清楚
Amber?
安芭盧?
No monsters in the vicinity.
附近沒有魔物
No signs of life either.
也沒有活著的人
Do you feel lonely?
妳很寂寞嗎
Stay sharp. I smell blood.
小心點 有血的味道
I think I'm going to be blind!
我的眼睛要瞎了
Is this better?
這樣比較好嗎
These are armours of empire soldiers.
這是帝國兵的盔甲
They must have fought monsters here.
他們在這裡和魔物交手了吧
They didn't have time to mourn their dead.
連哀悼死者都做不到
The battle must have been intense.
可見戰況非常悽慘
Perhaps the world is already...
說不定這個世界已經…
What's wrong?
怎麼了
Go!
上啊
The empire's soldiers!
帝國軍
They are still fighting.
還有人在戰鬥啊
Satou, use that.
佐藤 用那個…
Satou?
佐藤?
I know.
我知道
The Abyss King...
深淵王
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物語》
Go down from here.
從這裡下去
You can approach the demon army from the side.
就能從側邊接近魔物大軍
Use the element of surprise to take down the Abyss King.
趁虛而入攻擊深淵王
Yes.
好
Satou.
佐藤
Don't worry.
別擔心
We have all the rings.
戒指都到齊了
I have you with me.
還有大家幫我
It all happened sooner than expected,
雖然比我預期的還突然
but this is the reason we came back.
但我們就是為此回來的
I'm counting on you, Ring King.
交給你了 戒王
I'm betting all my hopes on you.
妾身把所有希望都賭在你身上
You can do it, Lord Satou.
佐藤陛下一定沒問題的
Yeah.
嗯
You're our best hope, Ring King.
全靠你了 戒王
Satou.
佐藤
I'll be waiting for you.
我等你回來
Yes.
好
I'll be right back.
我去去就回
You finally came.
你來了啊
Heir of the rings.
戒指的繼承者
You've done well,
一路走來辛苦你了
New King.
新的王
Young man,
少年
combine the power.
讓力量合而為一吧
Incredible.
好厲害
Do not show any mercy.
接下來不用手下留情
He did it.
成功了
No.
不對
This can't be happening.
不會吧
How come?
怎麼會
The rings are the truth of this world.
戒指就代表世界的真理
The Abyss must be destroyed.
深淵一定會毀滅
The world shall have salvation.
世界應該會得救
Am I not worthy enough?
憑我…難道不行嗎
Satou!
佐藤
Heir of the rings.
戒指的繼承者
You are also a puppet who knows nothing.
你也是什麼都不知道的傀儡嗎
No...
不行
This can't be right!
這樣子怎麼可以
Our duty...
我們的使命
and the legends, do they mean nothing?
還有傳說到底算什麼
I'm going to fight.
我要上了
We can't lose Satou here.
我們不能在這裡失去佐藤
Don't worry.
別擔心
I won't let him die.
我不會讓他死的
All those stories about being too weak to move a finger
連一根手指都動不了這種事
are true, after all.
還真的會發生呢
Return to the Abyss!
回歸深淵吧
Women who wield the rings...
持有戒指的女人們
What are you doing here?
妳們為什麼來了
We can't just watch you die.
我們怎麼能袖手旁觀啊
Granart!
葛蘭納托
Darn it! Let me go!
可惡 放開我
We are outnumbered.
數量太多了
Satou!
佐藤
Lord Satou!
佐藤陛下
Sorry, everyone.
各位 對不起
Satou!
佐藤
Hime...
小姬…
Satou, good morning.
佐藤 早安
Hime?
小姬
Good morning.
早安
Do you promise
你發誓
to be true to her in sickness and in health
無論生病或健康的時候
and love her
都會愛著她
and honour her all days of your life?
尊敬她並珍惜她嗎
I do.
我發誓
Gramps.
爺爺…
You're finally awake, Satou.
佐藤 你醒啦
I see.
原來如此
Am I dead?
我死了嗎
Don't be silly.
你在說什麼啊
We're not dead yet.
我們還沒死
What is going on?
這是怎麼回事
Master Alabaster saved us.
阿拉巴斯塔閣下救了我們
Well done, Great Sage.
不愧是大賢者
Give me a break, you're exaggerating.
少來了 我才沒那麼厲害
I used up all of my strength
我光是想辦法製造機會
just to create an opening between you and the Abyss King.
讓你們遠離深淵王就耗盡全力
We can't afford to lose the rings just yet.
我們果然不能失去戒王的力量
That's right!
對了
If you made it out alive, is Mr. Marse...
爺爺沒事就代表馬爾斯先生也…
Prince Marse is alive.
馬爾斯王子也沒事
You must thank her for everything.
一切都是她的功勞
It's you...
妳是…
It's been a while, Ring King.
好久不見 戒王
I'm from the royal family of Lomka,
我是風之洛姆加王族
Princess Sumaragdi Lomka.
絲瑪拉格蒂·洛姆加
Thanks to Sumaragdi,
多虧有絲瑪拉格蒂
we managed to break through the Abyssal Creatures' ranks and escape.
我們才能逃離深淵魔物的包圍
I've been secretly protecting Master Alabaster.
我一直暗中守護阿拉巴斯塔大人
When I saw danger closing in on him,
但是看到危險逐漸逼近他
I got anxious.
讓我坐立不安
And because of that,
多虧這樣
I had the chance to help Master Alabaster.
我才能幫上阿拉巴斯塔大人的忙
He gave my life
賦予我的生命
such a wonderful purpose.
如此美好意義的阿拉巴斯塔大人
He truly is...
果然是我的…
The monsters have retreated.
魔物們也折返回去了
The Abyss King must have suffered great damage as well.
可見深淵王也受到重創
So, the attack wasn't completely useless.
原來還是有效果啊
Don't be ridiculous.
你在說什麼
You did great back there.
那已經是很棒的結果了
None of us could have landed a hit on him.
憑我們根本傷不了他一根寒毛
Splendid work, Satou.
你做得很好 佐藤
Great Sage,
大賢者閣下
how is the overall situation now?
現在整個局勢到底怎麼樣
Soon after your departure,
你們走後沒多久
the Abyss King's army began launching assaults.
深淵王的軍隊就開始發動進攻
The empire's army tried to hold them off at the mountain range.
帝國軍想盡辦法 把他們擋在大山壁那裡
Even I went in to assist them.
我也去幫忙了
But not much could be done.
但什麼都做不了
We could only run from the monsters.
只能一直逃
What about Marsa?
麻薩呢
How is Marsa now?
麻薩現在怎麼樣了
Every nation is holding its ground gallantly.
每個國家都守在自己的領土 努力奮戰
Marsa will be fine.
麻薩不會有事的
Prince Marse is there to help.
因為那裡有馬爾斯王子在
But not only is the number of monsters not decreasing,
可是魔物的數量不但沒有減少
more are pouring in.
還一直增加
Things will get worse.
情況可說是越來越糟
Thankfully, I never abandoned my hope.
幸好我一直沒放棄期望
You are finally back.
總算等到你們歸來了
Master Alabaster, it's almost daybreak.
阿拉巴斯塔大人 天要亮了
The return of the Ring King.
戒王回來了
All the princesses are here.
公主們也到齊了
It's a dawn of hope ahead of us.
黎明看起來充滿希望
The Ring King is back!
戒王回來了
The five princesses are with him, too.
他帶著五位公主回來了
There are monsters everywhere. We are trapped here.
到處都是魔物 不能到外面去
But you are back, Ring King.
但是戒王您回來了
Everything will be all right.
所以不會有事吧
Yes. You can count on me.
對 交給我吧
I will save this world!
我會拯救這個世界
Well,
好了
time to discuss our course of action.
關於今後的事
Before that,
在說這個之前
please explain yourself.
請你先好好解釋一下
I thought we could defeat the Abyss King by collecting
不是只要收集到所有戒指
all the rings.
就能打倒深淵王嗎
"STARES" Well... I mean...
(凝視) 不…那個
Gramps, level with me.
爺爺 你就直說吧
Do I lack the strength?
是我的力量不夠嗎
I think I know why Satou
我大概知道為什麼
couldn't defeat the Abyss King.
佐藤沒辦法打倒深淵王
The black rings the Abyss King was wearing
深淵王戴著的那些黑色戒指
were never mentioned in any tales.
在傳說裡完全沒有提到過
Black rings?
黑色戒指?
Pretty much like a black copy of our rings.
就像這個戒指的黑色翻版
They don't exist in my records.
我的紀錄裡沒有
The dwarves were unaware of their existence.
矮人並不知道它的存在
But based on all the sources,
但是從各種知識見聞來看
we can confirm that the Ring King sealed the Abyss King away.
都能確定是戒王封印了深淵王
However, I have no idea how much power is needed
不過想做到這點需要多大的力量
to accomplish that.
我不知道
Well? What should we do now?
那你說我們該怎麼辦
There is only one way.
我們能採取的辦法只有一個
Figure out a way to unleash the greater power of the rings before the next fight!
那就是在下次交手前 想辦法讓戒指發揮更大的力量
In other words,
換句話說
Satou must strengthen his bonds with the Ring Princesses.
就是讓佐藤和戒指公主加深情感
Strengthening of bonds...
加深情感
Does that mean...
這意思不就是…
We're making babies.
生孩子
That's one way to do it.
那也是一個辦法
Seriously?
也是嗎
Satou!
佐藤
Mr. Marse!
馬爾斯先生
What are you doing here?
你怎麼會在這裡
I heard that you were coming back,
我聽說你們回來了
so I came.
就飛奔過來
I want to see you guys again,
就算只有一下子也好
even for just a brief moment.
我想見你們一面
All right, time to get down to business.
好了 接下來才是正題
Legend has it that the Ring King and the Ring Princesses
據說過去戒王和戒指公主們
went into the battle together.
曾經一起上戰場
To unleash the power of the rings,
想發揮戒指的力量
you need the spirit to fight as one
可能需要共同奮戰的意志
and the strength to match that spirit.
以及支持這個意志的實力
That could be the key to everything.
也說不一定
Strength...
實力嗎
I don't know about Saphir, Amber, and myself, but...
先不論我和瑟菲珞還有安芭盧
The two of us can't really fight.
我們兩個實在不行
That's the problem.
問題就在這裡
You must acquire the strength befitting the Ring King's wife.
大家要讓自己擁有 配得上戒王妻子的力量
Yes, that means training is needed.
沒錯 這是修行
In other words, bridal training!
換句話說 就是新娘訓練
The Ring King's bedroom is this way.
戒王的寢室在這裡
The princesses are ready for you.
公主們已經先進去等您了
Satou mustered the determination
佐藤已經下定決心為了我們
to return to this world and fight for all of us.
重新回到這個世界戰鬥
Therefore, we must be determined as well.
所以我們也必須下定決心
Ring King, rest well and replenish your strength.
戒王 你就好好養精蓄銳吧
Here, start with the lady you like.
來 從你喜歡的女人開始選
Of course, I don't mind if everyone joins.
當然 大家一起來也沒問題
What now?
怎麼了
Isn't it every man's dream to have a harem?
後宮不是男人的夢想嗎
See? The Ring King looks troubled.
看吧 戒王一臉困擾的樣子
Such is the nature of a catfolk who doesn't understand emotions.
無法理解情感的獸人就是這副德性
"FURIOUS" What?
(火大) 什麼
What did you say?
妳說什麼
You're just a pipsqueak who got overtaken by the little sister!
被妹妹超前的小矮子還敢這麼囂張
Huh?
什麼
Saphira has nothing to do with this.
跟瑟菲菈沒關係吧
See? I was right!
什麼啊 被我說中了嗎
Keep your voice down.
居然像這樣大吼大叫
I'm not yelling!
我才沒有大吼大叫
Bridal training, huh?
新娘訓練啊
You look quite happy.
妳好像很開心呢
Nah.
沒有啦
You've done so much for me,
一直都是你在為我努力
I should do the same for you.
我也要為你努力才行
Could that be...
那個該不會是…
My family consisted of my parents, me,
我的家人有爸爸 媽媽
and my little sister.
和一個妹妹
My sister was left in this world.
我妹妹被留在這個世界
We haven't seen each other in ten years.
我們已經十年沒見了
My parents rest here now.
而我的父母在這裡
Father, Mother, I am home.
爸爸 媽媽 我回來了
I was too young at the time.
我當時還小
I could barely remember their faces.
只隱約記得他們的臉
But they sacrificed themselves
但他們為了保護我
to save me.
犧牲了自己的性命
This man over here
這個人
is my husband.
是我的老公
Thank you, Satou.
謝謝你 佐藤
I am here again,
我能回到這裡
thanks to you.
都是多虧了你喔
Krystal.
克莉絲朵
Gramps, when did you get here?
爺爺 你什麼時候來的
"Father, Mother, I am home."
從妳說"爸爸 媽媽 我回來了"
That's when.
這裡開始
You were here all along!
好早就來了
It's nothing to feel embarrassed about.
我覺得沒什麼好害羞的
It's a touching story.
故事非常感人
By the way, let's talk about the magic training.
對了 關於魔法修行
I'll give it my best. Please train me.
我會加油的 請多指教
No, I'm not here to train you.
不 不是我來教
I found the perfect mentor for you.
我幫妳找了一位適合的老師
She should be here very soon.
對方說很快就會到
What is that?
那是什麼
It's you.
就是你啊
Not bad.
挺不錯的嘛
My name is Morion Ravri Nokanatika.
我是茉莉昂·拉布莉·諾卡那堤卡
Please to see you, Sister.
請多指教 姊姊
And you too,
還有
Brother-in-law.
姊夫
Brother-in-law?
姊夫?
Morion Ravri Nokanatika...
茉莉昂·拉布莉·諾卡那堤卡
You're Hime's...
小姬的…
little sister!
妹妹?